The populist politician Manfred Fest
was struck by a sniper in Munich.
Fest was visiting his son. Elias Fest
at the Saint Elizabeth hospital.
Argh!
This has sparked speculation
concerning a connection
between these incidents.
When a sniper finds a rifle
that allows him to make
a shot at that distance.
that rifle is a keeper.
There's a gun maker
who's been trying to do this.
His name is Norman Stoke.
I have an asset in Belfast.
Codename Sparrow.
If Larry knew who I was talking to.
he'd kill me.
- She has a daughter. Emma.
- Whose streets?
- I know I can find him.
- Don't let me down.
Who's the target?
Ulle Dag Charles.
River is a revolutionary technology.
Can you get to him?
It'll cost.
We've got a serious problem
with your student.
She's arrested.
In Germany. supporters of Manfred Fest
continue to call for the upcoming
federal elections to be postponed.
His political opponents deny that
their resistance to this
is a mark of disrespect
to Fest and his family.
Manfred Fest's son. Elias was also...
Who's Sparrow?
Gimme. Gimme. Gimme.
Gimme. Gimme. Gimme. Gimme. Gimme.
- Alison. just give me a moment.
- Morning.
You're a fucking bitch. you know that?
Alison. what's going on?
Don't tell me this is a coincidence.
You suddenly turning up out the blue
and next thing Emma's arrested.
They're not letting me speak to her.
And I know you're
doing this to get at me.
I've got nothing to do with it.
You're a liar.
Why are you calling me. Alison?
You know fucking fine rightly
why I'm calling.
I know you can get her out.
You got me out.
Yeah. you had
something to offer back then.
Just get me Norman's phone number.
and I'll do the rest.
And I want it today.
The preliminary report says Emma
had a preexisting heart condition.
She could've died anywhere.
But she died in a police cell.
and you put her there.
The man who killed Manfred Fest
will kill again. unless we stop him.
So. collateral damage?
- I wouldn't put it that way.
- What way would you put it?
A girl died who shouldn't have died.
This is Mr Carver.
He cleans up messes for us.
And you're very lucky
he's here to clean up yours.
The girl was in police custody.
That makes the police
legally responsible.
but it is my job to make certain.
one hundred percent.
that MI6 can't be connected in any way.
So. who knows you were
at the police station?
Everything went through Gillespie.
- The copper?
- Yeah.
He's the only one
who even knows my name.
I'll have a word with Gillespie.
make sure no one else can identify her.
- Anyone else?
- No.
- You're sure?
- Yes.
Let's hope Gillespie can be trusted.
We need to
close this operation down. now.
I spoke to Sparrow this morning.
She's on the hook.
Did you tell her that
her daughter's dead?!
I did not.
You're in a hole
and you want to keep digging?
A major political figure
has been assassinated.
and there's a strong probability
that the gun was
made by a British gunmaker.
and I have a lead on him.
Are you saying we should
just walk away?
This is a wild goose chase. and it's
not helping our department's reputation.
We should offload this
to the Central Europe desk.
I promised the Germans we'd help.
Emma's... is unfortunate.
but it's ends and means.
And in this instance. ends trump.
Alison cannot find out about Emma.
Once that news breaks. I've lost her.
I can buy you some time.
How long?
Twenty-four hours maybe.
You'd better get to work.
Come on.
Yes?
I've got some good news.
I've talked to my bosses.
and I can get Emma out.
- Great. right?
- Yes.
But I need you to get me Norman's
phone number. and I need it today.
Don't worry. Emma'll be home soon.
Morning.
Hmm. I can see when you are...
When you go to that place you go
when you are thinking about work.
I'm here.
Only half.
Tell the other half to come.
I miss him.
There's someone
I've been working with. has. um...
Well. they've misunderstood
their obligations to me.
Is it money?
Yeah.
A lot?
What are you gonna do?
It's not just the money.
It's that if it were to get out
that someone had...
got away without paying me.
it. it hurts the brand.
Which is a problem.
I know.
And if he steals from you...
he steals from your family.
which is me and Carlito.
So you tell me where he lives.
and I get the money he owes.
What?
- I will do it. trust me.
- Yeah. I don't fucking doubt it.
I do not doubt that.
But don't worry. I'll sort it.
There's another deal brewing.
Is it big?
Well. it would mean that I could
spend a lot more time with you two.
The people you work for think that.
because they pay you
a lot of money. they...
own your soul.
What is that look?
What?
- Sometimes you look at me and...
- What?
I don't know.
No. what do you mean?
Sometimes you look at me?
- And... what do you mean?
- I don't know.
Sometimes you look at me and what?
What do you see?
- I see a motherfucker.
- Fuck you.
I was shaving this morning.
and it hit me.
The economists are wrong.
We could easily lose
half the world's population
and there'd be no downside.
Would have to be the right half.
of course.
Now. the question is. can we trust
the man who killed Manfred Fest?
Leonora asked me to find you the
best. That's what I've done.
He's clearly capable.
but a hundred mil is
a hell of a lot of money to spend.
Well. we only pay if he delivers.
And if he delivers. it'll be worth it.
Thank you. Good to see you.
Thanks for coming in.
Ulle Dag Charles. you're about
to launch a product. River.
which you're promising will deliver
global economic justice.
Why is the richest man on the planet
so interested in economic justice?
Well. we should all be
interested in economic justice.
It's a simple as that. Right?
Your parents were leftist radicals.
Some would say you're
trying to please mom and dad.
Oh. come on.
Look. money runs like water
into the pockets of the superrich
and stays there.
Instead it should run into
reservoirs for future generations.
And the only way to do that
is total financial transparency.
Right?
Super-rich like you?
Yeah.
Do you want everyone
to see into your bank accounts?
Well. I've got nothing to hide.
But there are people out there.
with a lot to hide.
and River is gonna...
We have very little time.
This has got to be done
before he releases this River thing.
Do I make myself clear?
Shall we do this? Let's have a go.
Blow the candles out!
Come on. Carlito!
Well done!
Presents!
Presents! Presents! Presents!
Carlito. all these presents for you!
Do you want to give him this one?
I actually... I made you something.
little one.
- You did?
- Yeah. in New York.
- Did you have time for this?
- Yeah.
Look. look. look!
Shall we have a look?
What's this?
Look at this. Carlitos.
Look!
This...
Little one.
this is an American plane.
Daddy. no. don't...
Hey.
Guys. no posting. you know.
Mama?
OK. OK.
They know.
- I promise. they know.
- Sorry. I know you know.
- You know.
- I know.
- What?
- Happy birthday.
You alright. love?
I can't bear to think of Em
all alone in a cell.
Aye...
And over there in London.
At least if they were holding her
here. she'd be with her own people.
Love...
We've both been through this.
The first time they arrested me.
they had me petrified.
But you survived.
She's not like us. Larry.
She needs us there.
I wanna go over.
Where we gonna get the money for that?
- You could ask Norman?
- Norman?
Well. Norman has loads of money.
You're in touch with him. aren't ya?
- Do you know where he is?
- I can't run to my wee brother
every time we get in trouble.
This is serious. They're saying
she bottled a policewoman.
She needs us over there!
Charles.
Hi.
No pain.
- A lot of children. eh?
- Always. Always children.
Different for you. no? You...
- you only child?
- Yeah.
- Sorry. Sorry. um...
- No.
You know. Charlie.
my... my English is very difficult.
You always say that. Alvaro.
but you speak very good English.
- Nah.
- No. it's...
Spanish is impossible for me...
- so it's all good...
- No! Your Spanish is better.
- Really?
- Mm.
You know. I never tell you.
Always when you go away.
I tell everybody.
don't worry. I here.
I look. everything is perfect.
everything is OK.
- So... you need anything...
- Yeah.
- I can do.
- That's very kind. Alvero.
and I appreciate it. Honestly.
Look. Charlie. One thing.
- I have a friend. OK?
- OK.
And my friend has a... has a bar.
And he offered to...
How do you say...
- To. to sell. to sell.
- Yeah.
A part. half of the bar.
OK.
So. if you're interested.
I can take you to my friend.
and the three can speak.
see if it's good.
I think that would be...
I think we should do that.
But I think maybe when I...
perhaps when I come back.
- Here?
- Yeah.
Do you know what?
Give me one. one second.
I've just gotta make a quick call.
Yeah. I gotta... Er. it will be quick.
I'll be one minute.
Yeah.
- No. Not again. please.
- I'm so sorry.
- Oh. come on.
- I know.
They know it's his birthday. They
just have no empathy. these people.
- I'm so sorry.
- You arrived only yesterday.
I know. I know I did.
Guys. I'm so sorry.
I'm gonna have to head off.
Bye. bye little one. Bye. bye.
Happy birthday.
I love you. I'll see you soon.
I'll see you soon.
- Ciao.
- OK. I'm driving you.
No. I booked a cab.
- You can't leave this.
- No. I'm driving you.
Charlie.
Hey. I here. OK?
Yeah. Thanks. Alvaro.
Bye. guys.
- Bye! Adios!
- Ciao!
- Bye!
- Say bye. Daddy!
The BND said the guard was convinced
he was talking to the real Ralf.
The voice. the intonation. the sarcasm.
Apparently. everything was perfect.
So our man is a mimic.
And if he's a mimic.
he's good with language.
so he's not necessarily German.
Er. enlarge the backpack for me?
Waxed canvas.
Of course
he's taken the maker's tab off.
Enhance that so I can see where it was.
Yeah. Grab some screenshots of that.
Done. Shall I move on?
Yeah.
So he's righthanded...
Oh whoa. stop it there.
Enlarge.
Keep going.
Whoa stop. stop. stop.
Browning HiPower. Mark III.
Why would you go for a nine mil
when you could have something
with a lot more stopping power?
Why would you do that?
That's it?
You've gone to that place again.
- Oh my God.
- I'm here.
I'm here.
Yeah.
Don't humiliate me.
I love you.
I love you. too.
- Hola.
- How are you?
- To Santa Justa. please.
- Yes. sir.
Hi. this is Charles.
Please leave a message
and I'll get back to you.
There you go. love.
Larry. please. Call Norman.
I've called him already.
Twice.
If he doesn't call back soon.
I'll try him again. OK?
The maker's tab was
a sort of mountain range shape.
She...
Hello. yes. I'm looking for a very
specific backpack.
Charcoal grey. wax canvas.
Mountain range maker's tab.
Isabel's expecting you.
The sniper's British.
Don't even joke about that.
- And he's probably ex-British Army.
- You know that how?
You need military training to make
a shot at even half that distance.
Doesn't necessarily mean
he's one of ours.
He used a Browning HiPower
Mark III to kill Elias's bodyguard
and to wound Elias.
The HiPower was standard
British Army issue until 2013.
A lot of armed forces used the HiPower.
He had a backpack made by
a small UKbased startup
called The Perfect Pack.
The backpack went on sale
eight months ago.
There are only two retailers.
both in Leeds.
and neither ships internationally.
That means he was here. in the UK.
Or an accomplice picked it up for him.
No. Our man works alone.
Snipers work with a spotter.
Not this one.
He was alone when he shot Elias
and he was alone
when he left the apartment building.
So we think the sniper is British.
and the gun maker is British.
- Have you heard from Sparrow?
- She knows what she has to do.
By tomorrow morning she'll know
her daughter's dead.
and bang goes your leverage.
- I need more time.
- No.
I'm this close.
Bianca... we're already
on very thin ice.
I suggest you encourage Sparrow
to give you what you want.
By tomorrow.
Hello. my love.
What time are you gonna be home?
Err. not sure. Not too late. I hope.
OK. OK.
My brothers are coming at eight.
I'm cooking moussaka.
It's so complicated. though.
They better love it.
They will. Um. OK. I'll see you then.
OK. don't be late. Yep. Alright.
- Love you.
- Bye. bye. bye. bye. bye.
OK.
If our sniper was ex-Army.
he would've done his sniper training
at Pirbright if he was a Para
or Household Division.
If he had another cap badge
he would've gone to
the Infantry Battle School at Brecon.
We need them to go
through their records.
And what are we looking for?
An exceptional candidate.
Righthanded. Tall. White.
And how far back do we want them to go?
Assuming our man is under fifty...
I'd say about thirty years.
Who is this?
We met in Sweden.
How can I help' you?
I have spoken to my colleagues. and
we feel there's a deal to be done.
But we need to meet in person
to work out the details.
We're not meeting again.
For a deal of this size.
we believe a meeting is essential.
It has to be in person and it has to
be in the next 48 hours.
Yeah. well.
I'm afraid that's not happening.
We've already shown you
a million dollars of good faith.
If we can't meet in the next 48 hours.
we'll have to move on.
Hello?
You'll have to come to me.
I'll send instructions.
I look forward to it.
- Hi!
- Oh. hey.
Oh. just about on time.
This looks great!
Oh wow. OK. OK. OK. OK.
Er. Tempranillo. perfect for moussaka.
- Grenache blanc. This is perfect.
- Yeah. see. I do listen to you.
Or they told her at the wine shop.
Oh wow.
She's never that excited to see me.
- Hey.
- Hello.
- You good?
- I wasn't sure which one.
- It's absolutely good.
- Dad.
Absolutely fine.
Come on. bring it in. There he is.
- You alright?
- Mum sends love.
Good to see you. man.
- I'm good. man. You alright?
- Hi.
- Good to see you.
- Looking good. looking good.
- You good?
- Hi!
How are you?
- I'm good. you?
- Yeah.
I wanted a Bacardi and Coke.
- You asked for a Gin.
- I asked for a Bacardi.
And get a pack of crisps
while you're at it.
Aye.
Second time lucky.
Vodka and Coke.
Gin and Coke?
You're not funny. Larry.
Do you like it?
You see the gods
on Mount Olympus. yeah.
they used to eat this thing
called ambrosia.
But then Jasmine goes and sends them
up some of her famous moussaka.
- You know what they said?
- No.
You don't know what they said?
They said. Fuck ambrosia.
Because from now on
its Jasmine's moussaka.
- Oh. god.
- What is he talking about?
- It's a brainy compliment.
- I can see that the classics
- aren't wasted on you. Adam.
- Come on.
Mm-hmm.
One second.
Uh... top up?
Please give characters two.
three and six of your telephone ID.
Zero. one. nine.
How I can help?
I need a priority location on a phone.
- Speaking as a former teenage boy...
- A very long time ago.
Mm-hmm. that's what we do.
We fuck it up. That is true.
- It's facts.
- Seriously?
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Jas.
Um. I'll see you soon. boys.
Er. call us when you get there. yeah?
I'll try.
Ms Jansone?
This has been left for you.
Thank you.
Norman's still at
the location in Belarus.
I have nine missed calls from Sparrow.
Does she know about Emma?
Not yet.
But at some point soon
she's going to have to be told.
If Sparrow finds out. she'll tell
Larry. who will tell his brother.
I'll see what I can do.
Spencer's waiting in arrivals.
He'll get you across the border.
Just make sure you get Norman.
- We're counting on you.
- Yeah.
- Spencer?
This way.
The Latvians know we're
operating on their turf.
They're friendly.
but Belarus is very hostile.
We need to get to the target
as soon as possible.
The journey to Smarhon's six hours.
Toby's our wheels.
Colin'll be with us for the grab.
Let's go.
You can keep looking straight ahead.
Have you left your phone at the hotel?
Of course.
Good.
My clients need to know
if you think it's possible.
speaking as a professional?
Well. er. UDC may think he's God.
but that doesn't mean he's immortal.
We're still some way apart on the fee.
Perhaps we can meet in the middle?
We're not terrorists.
You know. we're patriots.
We're defending our way of life.
I have fuck all interest in
why you want him dead.
A hundred million is a big ask.
You're paying me to kill him.
I am charging you for getting away.
And. speaking as a professional.
getting away
is an important consideration.
It's half in advance. half on delivery.
No. Half up front won't fly. but
I am authorised to pay you
a commencement fee
of twenty million dollars.
I could do that today.
Would that be acceptable?
Yeah.
The job has to be
completed by the 28th.
I'm not in the habit of being hurried.
UDC releases River on the 28th.
It's nonnegotiable.
Can you do it?
Once the payment is in my bank
account. I will get to work.
Why are you still in Munich?
It's been nearly a week
since you killed Manfred Fest.
Have you loose ends to tie up?
We don't want you doing anything
that attracts attention or
that puts you in jeopardy
that's not in service of the job.
There are no loose ends.
Good.
Then we have a deal.
We have a deal.
Keep looking straight ahead.
In future communications...
we'll use the code name
Rodin for the target.
Rodin.
Very good.
And we'll need a code name
for you. too.
Why not the Jackal?
Why not?
Sir. thank you so much
for your patience.
Mr. Thirsk. So that payment was
made from a company account.
HelleLinie.
HelleLinie. Well.
what can you tell me about HelleLinie?
I'm afraid we're not authorised
to give out that information.
but the national company register
is available online.
Is there anything else I
can help you with?
Er. no. thank you.
Twenty minutes to the border.
Norman hasn't moved.
40 meters out at the rear. Moving.
Moving.
25 meters out at the rear. Moving.
Approaching front door. Moving.
Moving.
10 meters out at the rear. Moving.
Everyone in position?
Two in position.
Norman! The house is surrounded!
Throw your weapons down
and come outside!
On my count.
Three. two. one... breech!
Man down!
Fuck.
We're two down.
Target escaping on foot.
In pursuit.
Fuck!
Bravo to Tango. We were
set up. He knew we were coming.
Two pax down.
Immediate extraction from X-Ray now.
30 seconds out.
Fuck. You.